《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously, on "The Flash"...
震波必须重生
Vibe must live again.
我已经不是纳什了  我是遭弃者
I am no longer Nash. I am Pariah.
我释放了反监视者
I freed The Anti-Monitor.
现在我被迫做见证人
Now I am forced to bear witness
接近警报
附近监测到反物质波
看着他摧毁一个又一个世界
as he destroys world after world.
奥利弗牺牲了他自己来建造这个新世界
Oliver scarified himself to create this new world.
我们帮助奥利弗重启宇宙的时候
Our Earths must have merged
我们的地球肯定是汇聚成一体了
when we helped Oliver reboot the Universe.
我们如今全都生活在同一个地球了
We all live on the same Earth now.
就是这同一个家伙
This is the same guy that kidnapped
绑架了你表姐伊丝丽兰萨
your cousin Esperanza
并且把她变成了超能力刺客
and turned her into a meta-assassin.
你询问的那家伙被杀死了
The guy you questioned was killed in the same lot
就在你询问他的那个地方  还是同一天
you questioned him, on the same day.
有强大的紫外线能量从这个东西中发出
There's major UV energy coming off this thing.
看来公民报小队有了新任务
Looks like Team Citizen has a new mission.
危机已经结束
欢迎回到中城吉特斯
大伙快请进
Come on in, folks.
喝了五个月的震波布奇诺外卖
After five months of Vibaccinos to-go,
欢迎大家光临全新的吉特斯
welcome to the new Jitters.
请用
Here you go.
大伙请记住
And remember, folks,
中城吉特斯永远都会存在  无论是雨天...
CC Jitters is here to stay, rain or--
举起手来  你们这群对奶泡狂热的法西斯
Hands in the air, you foam-loving fascists!
开什么玩笑  才刚开张就被抢
Are you kidding me? We're already being robbed?
吉特斯刚刚重新开张
Jitters just reopened
立刻就被恐怖分子袭击了
and was immediately attacked by terrorists.
我怎么一点也不惊讶
Why am I not surprised?
我去救那些爱喝拿铁的家伙
I'll go bail out those latte-sippers.
大伙  我来搞定
Guys, I got this.
你  打开收银机
You. Open the register.
把里面所有东西都拿给我
Give me everything inside.
大哥  我们刚刚开张
Dude, we just reopened.
那里面基本上啥也没有
There's barely anything in there.
-真的吗  -对啊
- Really? - Yeah.
那我只好乱扫射一通了
Well, I'm gonna start blowing stuff up then.
糟了
Oh, crap.
抱歉我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
我喜欢你给咖啡店新做的装修
I love what you've done with the place.
闪电侠  闪电侠
Flash! Flash!
不必这样  大伙不必这样
Oh, stop. Stop it, guys.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第十集
抱歉
I'm sorry.
危机结束了  我们打败了坏人
Crisis is over, we beat the bad guy,
而你还在担心  是因为...
and you're still worried because...
因为
Because...
无限个地球
an infinite number of Earths
经历了全宇宙范围的热寂
experienced a cosmic heat death
从中只有一个地球重生了
from which only one Earth was rebuilt.
所以现在不但超人  超女
So now not only do Superman, Supergirl,
还有黑霹雳都存在于这个地球
and Black Lightning live here,
而且我们整个时间线都被改写成为
but now our entire timeline has been rewritten
他们一直都存在于这个地球
so that they've always lived here,
我都不记得自己有这么一件T恤
and I don't remember owning this shirt.
很棒的T恤
Great shirt.
再说了  这不是好事吗
Besides, isn't that a good thing?
我们现在成为一个快乐大家庭了
We're all one big, happy family now?
不  不
No. No!
不  不是
No, it is not.
这些家伙正在这一大团圆中捣乱
Not when these guys are crashing the reunion.
西斯科的人物指南名册
而我们曾在其他地球上的二重身
Not a single one of our doppelgangers
而据我所知  没有一个
survived to make it to Earth Prime,
活着来到这个始源地球
as far as I can tell,
可是一大堆坏蛋  外星人  更多的超能力者
but we did manage to pick up
却跟在我们屁股后面来到这个地球
a butt-ton of bad guys and aliens and more metas,
你知道最糟的是什么吗
and you know the best part?
最糟的是
The best part
之前的那群坏蛋又回来了
is a bunch of our old villains are back,
又搞出一堆新花样
with fresh paint jobs!
你什么时候有时间整理这些资料的
When did you have time to do all this?
伊甸队  尖峰人  彩虹大盗
Edencorp, The Top, Rainbow Raider.
我们的地球面临的威胁比以往都要多
Our Earth has more threats than ever,
我们都不知道他们是从哪来的
and we don't even know where they're coming from.
那是什么
What the hell was that?
管道坏了  暖气管道
Pipes-- bad pipes. The heating.
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
-放我出去  -你确定吗
- Let me out. - Are you sure?
因为你貌似把纳什锁在柜子里了
Cause it looks like you locked Nash in the closet.
没有
No.
放我出去
Let me out.
其中一根辅助管道泄露了
Okay, one of the auxiliary pipes was leaking,
所以他去修补
so he's patching it up
以换取加密电路
in exchange for a Crypto-circuit.
好吧  别放我出去
Fine, don't let me out.
我自己出去  多谢你了
I'll let myself out, actually, thank you very much.
我要使出力大无穷的肩力
I'm gonna put an Atlantean shoulder check
撞穿这扇门
into this door and bust right through.
-三  二...  -好吧
- In three, in two... - Okay.
一
In one!
你好啊
Sup?
-冰霜杀手  -现在只是冰霜
- Killer Frost. - It's just Frost now.
把加密电路给我
Give me my Crypto-circuit
不然我要打死你
or I'm gonna punch you in the throat.
你要的加密电路在我这  我可以给你
I have your Crypto-circuit, and I could give it to you,
但是
but, you know,
我真的不知道你要它来做什么
I'm not really sure what you'd need it for,
因为你是个探险家
because you're an adventurer,
你不是应该在某个地方探险吗
so shouldn't you be off somewhere, adventuring?
但绝对不是这里
Preferably not here.
猩猩城现在是始源地球的一部分了
Yeah, I mean, Gorilla City's part of Earth Prime now.
难道你不想去解开疑团吗
Don't you wanna go myth bust it?
不想
No.
猩猩都是无神论者
Gorillas are atheists.
你们在说笑吧
Are you kidding me?
不  我要去我挖的隧道做测试
No, I'm gonna run tests on my dig site
确保再也没人
to insure that nobody
会意外地重新打开反物质宇宙
ever accidentally reopens the anti-matter universe.
去做你的测试吧
Run your tests,
但是我已经做过测试了
but I've already run tests,
山洞一直处于关闭状态
and that cave is staying shut,
所以这里真的不需要你
so you're not really needed here.
你做过测试了  那这里真的需要我
Oh, you ran the tests? Then I'm really needed.
磁红女怎么样了
What happened to Magenta?
我觉得她人不错
I liked her.
这不是很好吗
Isn't it great?
《中城市民》
闪电侠阻止危机凯旋
这还是我们的头号要闻
It's still our number one story.
再次感谢你  朋友
Thanks again, friend.
爱瑞丝
Iris. Hey.
我刚从119号公路的一场汽车火灾中跑回来
I was running back from a car fire on Route 119,
看看我路上碰到了谁
and look who I found on the way back.
狄格
Dig, hey.
家人还好吗
How's the fam?
大家都很忙
Oh, everyone is very busy.
莱拉刚刚接手了一个新职位
Lila just accepted a new posting,
所以下周我们要带着孩子们去大都会了
so next week we'll be taking the kids to Metropolis.
我听说了
I heard.
那你现在不是应该在家里
So shouldn't you be at home,
帮忙打包东西吗
helping to pack boxes right now?
对
Right.
但是
But...
昨天宣读了奥利弗的遗嘱
Oliver's last will and testament was read yesterday,
然后
and, um,
他留了一样东西给你  巴里
he left something for you, Barry.
奥利弗的面具
Oliver's mask.
这是初版
It's the original.
这是我给他做的那个
This is the one I made him.
是啊  很有意思
Yeah, it's interesting,
因为奥利佛不是个多愁善感的人
because Oliver was never a man given to sentiment.
你看到这个了吗
Hey, do you see this?
就在左眼上边
Right above the left eye.
奥利弗有很多年没戴过这个了
Oliver hasn't worn this in years.
为什么上边有痕迹
Why is there a mark on it?
我不知道
I don't know.
费利西蒂干洗的时候不小心弄的
Felicity skimped on the dry-cleaning?
或者是他有意留下的
Or he left it on purpose.
正如你说的  奥利弗没那么多愁善感
I mean, you just said it. Oliver wasn't sappy.
如果说这面具是指向新威胁的线索呢
What if the mask is a clue to some new threat out there,
某种危险到不能写下的威胁
something too dangerous to put in writing?
巴里  你从一个小痕迹里看出这么多来
Barry, you got all that from a smudge mark?
未知
准备好交谈了
将会发送进一步指令
我不知道
I don't, uh... I...
爱瑞丝  你怎么想
Iris, what do you think?
我想你俩
Um, that you two
要自己来查明真相了
will have to figure this out on your own.
真对不起  宝贝  我得走了
I'm so sorry, babe, I gotta go
要去见线人  特紧急
meet with this source, like, right now.
没事  没关系
Yeah, no, that's fine.
去忙你的吧
Do your thing.
去报道新闻  我和迪哥调查这个
Break your story, and Dig and I can work on this.
就我们吗
We--we can?
不行吗
Can we?
你被跟踪了吗
Were you followed?
-没有  -你确定
- No. - You sure?
是的
Yes.
不不  不要录音
Uh, no--no--no recordings.
你追查的那些人  他们知道我声音
The people you're after, they know my voice.
这些人
These people
你说你了解他们不少
you say you've learned quite a bit about them,
那你肯定认识这个吧
so you should recognize this, right?
我为麦克洛奇技术公司工作了20年
I spent 20 years working for McCulloch Technologies.
开发部  机密的部门
R&D department, classified division.
然后这个家伙突然出现
And then this guy showed up,
说他叫马尔科姆·尚博德
said his name was Malcolm Strombard.
他被晋升到我们的小组
He'd been promoted into our group,
但是他没有任何科学常识
but he had no technical know-how.
但是上个秋季  我晚上去公司
But last fall, I-I came in late one night,
然后发现他拿着我们开发多年的
and I--I found him with the infrared photon rifle
红外线光子枪
we'd been developing for years.
第二天
The next day,
他和原型都消失了
he and the prototype were gone.
所以我就开始调查
So I started looking into it,
发现这个人  马尔科姆·尚博德
and this man, Malcolm Strombard,
实际上并不存在
he doesn't officially exist.
当然了  麦克洛奇里没人相信我
Of course, no one at McCulloch believed me,
所以他们开除了我
so they fired me.
派他去偷枪的团伙
The group that sent him to steal that rifle,
他们发现我在追查他
they found out I was after him.
他们杀了自己人
Oh, they killed their own man.
他们毁掉了太多的无辜生命
They have destroyed way too many innocent lives,
而且他们不会停手
and they will not stop
除非有人能曝光他们
unless someone helps us bring them to light.
像你一样的人  霍斯克先生
Someone like you, Mr. Huskk.
我能保持匿名吗
And I can stay anonymous?
没人会知道你的身份
No one will ever know your identity.
我会尽一切努力保证你的安全  我发誓
I will do whatever it takes to keep you safe, I swear.
那些人  他们不会
These people--they will not
这么容易就从阴影中出来
be brought out of the shadows easily.
他们生活在黑暗之中
They live in the darkness.
没有一丝光明
In the absence of light.
我没说
I didn't talk.
我没说  我发誓
I didn't talk, I swear!
他们称自己为...
They call themselves...
黑洞
Black Hole.
我送到了
发送给你下个目标
你在跟我说一个秘密组织
You're telling me that a secret organization
已经在中城运转了
has been operating in Central City
七年了
for seven years now?
是的  根据我的线人
Yes, and according to my source,
这个组织有个名字
they have a name.
黑洞
Black Hole.
我们一直在建时间线
We've been building a timeline.
看起来黑洞组织的活动
It looks like Black Hole's activity started
在粒子加速器刚爆炸之后就开始了
just after the Particle Accelerator exploded.
他们这段时间一直在绑架和训练超能力者
They've been abducting and training meta-humans,
就像我表姐伊丝丽兰萨或许更多人
like my cousin Esperanza and potentially others.
而且黑洞的影响范围远比
And Black Hole's reach goes far beyond
偷窃和训练超能力刺客大
theft and training meta-human assassins.
他们还涉及到国际军火贩卖
They are also involved in international arms deals.
然后杀掉所有他们认为已经暴漏的人
And they kill anyone they believe has been compromised,
包括我们的神秘人
including our mystery man,
现在比脆皮鸡还脆
who's now crispier than the chicken strips
阿莱格拉非要订外卖
Allegra insists on ordering for dinner.
那也比你的纯素甜甜圈强
Better than your vegan donuts.
爱瑞丝  你跟乔说过这些吗
Iris, have you told Joe about this?
我跟他说过了  但是爸他就会发动
Yeah, I have, but Dad would have to launch
一个反腐调查组来调查这个阴谋
a RICO investigation to pursue a conspiracy like this.
现在这是记者的领域
This is reporter territory now.
好了好了  我明白了
Okay, okay, look. Guys, I get it.
没有什么比记者的决心更强大
There's nothing stronger than a reporter's drive.
我能明显的从你们三个身上感觉到
I--I literally can feel it coming from all three of you.
但是作为你们的法律顾问  我跟你们说
But as your legal advisor, I gotta tell you...
我认为写这篇报道是个错误
I think that running this story is a mistake.
爱瑞斯  如果麦克洛奇不喜欢报道的东西
Iris, if McCulloch doesn't like what they read,
他们可以起诉你们诽谤
they can sue you for defamation.
我知道  我爸也担心
I know. My dad was worried
同样的事  但是我宁愿
about the same thing, but that's a risk
冒这个风险  塞西尔
that I'm willing to take, Cecille.
大伙  我们甚至还不知道是谁在操纵黑洞
Guys, we don't even know who's running Black Hole.
我们会发现的
We're gonna find out.
她说得对
Yeah, she's right.
记者从不放弃寻找真相
Reporters don't walk away from the truth.
我要去见
Now, I have a meeting
麦克洛奇科技的首席执行官
with the CEO of McCulloch Technologies,
约瑟夫·卡弗  在一小时后
Joseph Carver, in an hour.
我要看看他对最近发生的事情
So let's see if he's willing to comment
有没有什么评论
on what's been happening.
但是无论如何  做好去印刷厂的准备
But either way, be prepared to go to print.
我们无论有没有他的评论都要写这篇报道
We are running this story with or without his comment.
我知道这就像
I know it's sort of like
要求大海别那么多水
asking the ocean to be less wet,
巴里  你能不能  慢一点
but Barry, do you think you could, um, slow down?
狄格  你不想让我带你去取证室
Dig, you wouldn't let me speed you to the crime lab,
那我就只能把取证室带回这里
so I had to speed the crime lab here.
哥们  如果奥利弗真的想让你
Look, man, if Oliver really wanted you
调查一些事情  你不觉得他会给你
to look into something, don't you think he would've
直接留下信息而不是某种暗号
left you a note instead of some secret code?
因为奥利弗从来没跟你隐瞒过什么吗
Oh, because Oliver never kept a secret from you before?
面具上的沉积物痕迹
There's sediment traces on the mask
通常发现在中国北海的岛上
usually found on islands in the North China Sea.
-就像炼狱  -就像炼狱
- Like Lian Yu. - Like Lian Yu--
巴里  中国北海上可不止一个岛啊
Barry, there's more than one island in the North China Sea.
是啊  但是只有一个有米拉库鲁
Yeah, but only one with Mirakuru.
米拉库鲁
那个面具上真的有米拉库鲁
Does that mask really have Mirakuru on it?
安东·艾沃的超级士兵血清
Anton Ivo's super soldier serum.
你真的认为那个岛上还留有血清吗
You really think there's any of this stuff left on the island?
是啊  奥利弗一直觉得
Yeah, well, Oliver always thought that
会有一些样本能从艾沃的货船上保留下来
some samples could have survived on Ivo's freighter.
我们还不知道炼狱在危机后是什么样
We don't even know what the state of Lian Yu is post-Crisis.
如果有人搞到了米拉库鲁
I mean, if somebody got their hands on Mirakuru,
那他们就能变成一个活武器
they could become a living weapon.
或者复制血清再造一个军队
Or replicate it and build an entire army.
狄格  这  这一定就是
I mean, Dig, this--this is-- this has got to be
奥利弗给我留下面罩的原因
why Oliver left me the mask.
他想让我在炼狱对世界造成威胁之前
He wants me to find the last stash of Mirakuru
找到米拉库鲁和其相关的最后藏匿处
on Lian Yu before it threatens the world.
我知道你不想让我带你跑到那
Look, I know you don't want me to run you there,
但坐飞机要20个小时
but it's a 20-hour plane ride.
也太多了
That's too much.
看看你有多厉害
What you got?
我妻子和我创建这个公司时
My wife and I started this company
只有三名员工
with three employees.
现在我们有将近3000名
Now we have almost 3,000,
但我仍知道每个人的名字
but I still know each one of their names.
伊娃会想要如此的
It's what Eva would've wanted.
这很体贴  卡弗先生
That's very thoughtful, Mr. Carver.
请叫我约瑟夫
Joseph, please.
我特别喜欢《公民报》
I'm a huge fan of "The Citizen."
我能做些什么
How can I help?
我有一个线人
Well, I have a source
能证明
who can prove that
你的机密光子枪去年秋天
one of your classified Photon Rifles
被偷走了一支  现在落在
was stolen last fall and it's now in the hands
一个神秘组织的手中
of a secret organization
该组织和恐怖主义  绑架  非法武器交易
linked to terrorism, kidnapping, illegal arms deals,
还有谋杀相关
and murder.
你有什么评论
Would you care to comment?
莫里斯  告诉董事会我稍微晚会到
Maurice, tell the board I'm running a little bit behind.
韦斯特艾伦女士和我
Ms. West-Allen and I need to speak
要去一个更私密的地方聊下
someplace a little more private.
很好
Great.
麦克洛奇科技公司
你的线人是基恩·霍斯克吗
Your source-- it's Gene Huskk, isn't it?
我完全尊重你保护线人的需要
I completely respect your need to protect your sources,
但有些东西你需要知道
but there's something that you should see,
不宜报道的  为了霍斯克
off the record, for Huskk's sake.
请等一下
Just a sec, please.
有人渗入麦克洛奇的研发部门
Someone did infiltrate the R&D division
但并不是机密组织
here at McCulloch, but it wasn't a secret organization.
是黑曜石科技想盗取我们的模型
It was Obsidian Tech trying to steal one of our prototypes,
但霍斯克不肯接受
but Huskk couldn't accept that.
人力资源  纪律处分记录
他被说服了
He became convinced
相信有更大的阴谋
there was some larger conspiracy,
偏执消耗着他
and the paranoia consumed him.
他变得不安
He became troubled,
开始害怕其他员工
started scaring other employees.
我别无选择  只好让他离开
I had no choice but to let him go.
但我向你保证
But, uh, I can assure you
我们已经内部解决了这个问题
that we have dealt with this problem internally.
我们刚刚完成了我们的调查
We just completed our investigation,
我们明天就开始一个
and we're getting a whole new security system
全新的安保系统  新保安  新摄像头
starting tomorrow: new badges, new cameras.
这些工作
The works.
这儿没有什么可报道的
There's no story here.
恕我直言  卡弗先生
Well, with all due respect, Mr. Carver,
我觉得有
I think that there is.
可能是一个你不喜欢的
Maybe it's just one that you won't like.
韦斯特·艾伦女士  我做的所有事情
Ms. West-Allen, everything that I do,
都是在纪念我的夫人
I do in my wife's honor,
保护她的遗产
to protect her legacy.
像这样的报道真的会损伤
A story like this could really damage
我们公司的名誉
our company's reputation.
更别提会吓到我们的投资人
Not to mention, scare our investors.
我请求你
I'm asking you,
请不要写这个报道
please, don't run this story.
我理解
I understand.
你对于你的股东有责任
You have an obligation to your shareholders.
谢谢
Thank you.
但我对真相也有责任
But I have an obligation to the truth.
你被抢劫了  卡弗先生
You were robbed, Mr. Carver,
我明白这让人很尴尬
and I get that that's embarrassing,
但公众有权利在其他人受伤前
but the public deserves to know what happened
知道发生了什么
before anyone else gets hurt,
如果你不想发表评论的话
so if you wish to withhold comment,
也没有关系
that's fine...
我还是会写这篇报道
But I'm running this story either way.
麦克洛奇受秘密组织牵连
一个小时十万阅读量  这肯定破纪录了
100,000 views in one hour. That's gotta be a record.
《公民报》正式开始对抗黑洞
Citizen just fired its first shots at Black Hole.
这值得庆祝一下
This is a cause for celebration.
你满21岁了吗
Are you even 21?
我们最好等下再庆祝
I'd hold off on the balloons and bubbly.
麦克洛奇技术公司刚刚发来文件
McCulloch Tech just sent a memo.
他们要起诉《公民报》诽谤
They are suing "The Citizen" for defamation.
-这太荒唐了  -爱瑞丝
- This is ridiculous. - Iris.
伪造证词
Fabricated statements,
故意遗漏无罪证明
deliberate omission of exonerating evidence--
爱瑞丝  有什么不太对
Iris, something's not right.
卡弗只是想用诉讼费打垮我们
Carver is just trying to bury us in legal fees.
他只是想恐吓我们
He's just trying to scare us.
大家都趴下
Everybody down!
为什么有人朝我们开枪
Why is someone shooting at us?
是他们  是黑洞
It's them. It's Black Hole.
我们得离开这里
Okay, we--we gotta go.
好让他们在外面杀我们吗
So they can kill us outside?
听着  他们想要的是我
Okay, look, it's me that they're after,
你们去尖端科研实验室
okay, so you guys get to S.T.A.R. Labs.
我从纳什的隧道离开
I will make my way out through Nash's tunnels.
不行  我们不会离开你
No way. We're not leaving you.
我得确保线人的安全  好吗
Look, I have to make sure that my source is safe, okay?
确定之后我就去和你们汇合  我保证
Once I do, I will meet you there, I promise.
我们得走了  听我命令  好吗
Now we need to go. On my count, okay?
一  二  三  快走
One, two, three. Go!
走  走  快走
Go. Go, go, go, go, go.
无法连接
你们没事  发生什么了
You're okay. Oh. What happened?
黑洞试图暗杀爱瑞丝
Black Hole tried to assassinate Iris.
她去找她的线人了  塞西尔去了乔那里
She went to go find her source. Cecille went to Joe's.
-巴里呢  -他在炼狱岛
- Where's Barry? - He's in Lian Yu.
我一直试着联系他
I've been trying to radio him,
但是那里完全没有信号
but that place is a total dead zone.
你们用的那些滴答响的东西呢
What about those clicky things you guys use?
外推器不能用
The extrapolators don't work.
现在多元宇宙消失了
Now that the multi-verse is gone,
缺口的原理彻底改变了
the physics behind breaching has changed entirely.
但是别担心  冰霜正在寻找枪手
But don't worry, Frost is out there looking for the shooter.
她得小心一点  看到这些灼烧的痕迹了吗
She should be careful. Do you see these burn marks?
想杀我们的人用的是高强度射线
Whoever tried to kill us was using high-intensity light.
我的天啊
Holy crap.
我很高兴你们两个逃出来了
I'm glad you two made it out alive.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-我很好  -你很好
- Yeah, I'm fine. - You're fine.
太好了
Good.
你怎么没告诉我她们有危险
Yeah, why didn't you tell me that they were in danger?
我本来可以帮她们逃出来
Okay, I could've-- I could've gotten them out of there.
别对我发火  纳什
Don't come at me, Nash.
我没有义务给你提供信息
I'm not here to keep you in the loop.
你甚至不是这支队伍的成员
You're not even a part of this team.
这话太伤人了
Oh, that's so hurtful.
你的小队战绩怎么样
How's your little team doing in the standings?
-你的小队  -你不明白
- Your little team-- - Okay, you don't see
这就是我想说的问题
this is exactly what I'm talking about.
你不关心这支队伍
No, you don't care about the team.
你只有在对我们有企图的时候才跟我们合作
You only work with us when you want something from us.
别带上我
Yo, keep me out of this.
这次又怎么了
So what is it this time?
你发现了几个符号
You-- you got a couple glyphs
需要阿莱格拉帮你用X光扫描
you need Allegra to x-ray for you?
还是你想要打开
Oh, or maybe you just want to open up
另一个潘多拉魔盒
another Pandora's box of Hell.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
是我  我是唯一一个
I was the one to-- I was the only one
试图阻止危机的人
trying to stop Crisis.
那危机可是你引发的
A Crisis you started!
数十亿个世界  数万亿的人都消失了
Billions of worlds, trillions of people gone,
就像他们从没出生过一样
like they were never even born.
我为此付出了代价
And I paid for it!
作为代价我成了遭弃者  但我依然
As Pariah I paid for it and still managed
帮忙击败了反监视者
to help defeat the Anti-Monitor.
这对于死去的人来说没有任何意义
Which did nothing for the people who died.
奥利弗
Oliver.
哈里
Harry.
杰西
Jesse.
无数个哈里森·威尔斯
An infinite number of Harrison Wells's.
剩下的只有那个杀死多元宇宙的人
And we're stuck with the one who killed the multi-verse.
亲爱的  那是怎么回事
Babe, what the frak was that?
只是为了确保我们会从错误中吸取教训
Just making sure we learn from our mistakes.
爱瑞丝还在外面  伙计们
Iris is still out there, guys,
我们得在他们找到她之前
and we need to figure out who this assassin is
查出刺客是谁
before they get to her first.
谢天谢地你平安无事
Thank God you're safe.
我有危险  你也是
I'm not. Neither are you.
安全许可证
研发部
黑洞跟我们想的不一样
Black Hole isn't what we think.
天啊
Oh, my God.
镜子
Mirror.
-爱瑞丝  -老大  你没事
- Iris. - Boss, you're okay.
对  我很好  但我的线人就不同了
Yeah, no, I'm fine, but my source isn't.
那个要杀我的人先把他杀了
The person that tried to kill me got to him first.
西斯科  那个文件夹呢
Hey, Cisco, where's that binder?
-在这  -谢谢
- Right here. - Thanks.
在哪里  她在哪里
Where is it? Where is she?
纪美代·霍西博士
是她  纪美代·霍西博士
Her. Dr. Kimiyo Hoshi.
霍西
Hoshi...
她四年前消失了
She went missing four years ago.
她是来自东京的天文学家
She's an astronomer out of Tokyo
她的能力是将星光作为燃料
with the power to fuel starlight,
但她的超能力不够精确
but her meta-powers aren't precise enough
不能造成你给我看的照片里的那种损坏
to do the kind of damage you showed me in those photos.
如果她用光子步枪来瞄准他们呢
What if she used the Photon Rifle to focus them?
聪明  也许反光板碎片可以
Good thinking, maybe the reflector chip
聚集她的紫外线光子辐射
could condense her UV photon emissions.
步枪就是武器
The rifle is the weapon.
不  她是弹药
No, she's the ammunition.
所以黑洞把她变成了某种
So Black Hole turned her into some kind
邪恶光博士
of evil light doctor.
所以我们手上有一个全新的  更强大的
So we've got a brand new, more powerful,
以杀人为乐的光博士
murder-happy Dr. Light on our hands.
这是该死的始源地球赐给我们的
Another new meta-surprise
另一个超能力惊喜
courtesy of Earth-frakking-Prime.
你知道吗  其实
Actually, you know what?
霍西杀了我的线人
Hoshi killed my source,
但我设法保住了他给我的证据
but I managed to save some evidence that he gave me.
该死
Damn it.
你应该坐下
Hey, you should sit down.
我没事
I'm fine.
-你在外面受伤了吗  -我说了我没...
- Did you get hurt out there? - I said I'm fi...
呼叫冰霜  马上
Call Frost, now.
炼狱岛
这个原来在货船上吗
That was on the freighter?
如果还有什么东西留下  就在这里面
If there's anything left, it's in here.
把它打开  哥们  看看里面有什么
Open it up, man, let's see what's in it.
好
All right.
这不可能
This can't be right.
不  这不可能
No, this can't be right.
我把整个岛搜了十几遍
I--I--I searched the whole island a dozen times.
见好就收吧  哥们
Take the win, man.
已经没有米拉库鲁了  巴里
There's no more Mirakuru left, Barry.
不  奥利弗的面具  那是一个警告
No, I mean, Oliver's mask, it's a warning.
或者
Or...
也许它就只是原本
Maybe this is exactly what it was intended
所代表的意图  一件礼物
to be in the first place: a gift.
不  这不  这不可能只是一份礼物
No, man, no, it can't-- it can't just be a gift.
我们肯定漏掉了什么
I mean, there's got to be something we're missing.
如果有人先拿到了米拉库鲁呢
What if somebody got to the Mirakuru first?
真的吗  然后把盒子留下了
Really, and left the box behind?
我不知道
I don't--
我需要再做些测试
I need to run more tests.
或者我们为什么不叫来超查部
Or why don't we bring in the DEO?
或者打给费利西蒂或者西娅
Or call Felicity or Thea,
我们  我们不能就
I mean, we--we can't just
任由某人再创造一个丧钟
let somebody create another Deathstroke.
我们必须掐灭威胁的苗头
We have to stop this threat, man.
我必须完成奥利弗开始的任务
I mean, I have to finish what Oliver started.
巴里
Barry!
你还好吗
Are you all right, man?
我  那从没...
I'm--that's never...
我想  我只是有些沮丧
I--I--I'm just frustrated, I guess.
我想我知道这是怎么一回事了
Look, I think I know exactly what went on here.
奥利弗和西娅几年前来到这座小岛
Oliver and Thea came to this island a couple of years ago,
他们和以前住在这个牢房里的人进行了对峙
and they faced off with the man who used to live in this cell.
丧钟本人  斯莱德·威尔逊
Deathstroke himself, Slade Wilson.
奥利弗随身带着他的制服
Oliver brought his uniform with him.
也是为什么面具上会有土和米拉库鲁
Which is how he could have soil and Mirakuru on his mask.
这根本不是一个警告
It wasn't a warning at all.
你在找寻着一个
You're searching for a mission
根本就不存在的任务  巴里
that doesn't exist, Barry.
但是无论多少寻找也不能把奥利弗带回来
But no amount of searching is gonna bring Oliver back.
那个男人从一场斗争冲向另一场斗争
That man sprinted from crusade to crusade.
但是  巴里  人生不只是任务
But, Barry, life is more than just the mission,
不幸的是奥利弗知道的太晚了
and unfortunately Oliver learned that too late.
他也不会想要你走上同一条路
And he wouldn't want you going down that same path.
奥利弗牺牲自己才保存下这个地球  狄格
Oliver died so this Earth could live, Dig.
我必须做出任何我能做的事来保护它
I have to do everything I possibly can to protect it.
奥利弗不止是为了地球的生存才牺牲
Oliver died for more than this Earth's survival.
奥利弗牺牲了生命
Oliver laid down his life
是为了他爱的人能够好好活下去
so the people he loved could live theirs.
而这也包括你
That includes you.
人生就像一场马拉松  不是一场短跑  巴里
Life's a marathon, not a sprint, Barry.
慢下来  享受它
Slow down and enjoy it.
卡米拉让我来看看你
So Kamilla asked me to check on you.
你在看什么
What are you watching?
-我最近的实验让我的神经元兴奋起来  -哈里
- So my latest experiment jumpstarts my neurons... - Harry.
他们目前正以每秒120次交互
They're currently firing at 120 times per second.
我认为我们能达到200
And I think we can get to 200.
所以这是  你知道  进展
Yeah, so this is, you know, progress.
这是大进展
It's real progress.
我会告诉你的  想你
I'll let you know. Anyway, miss you.
他在重新获取他的智力
He was regaining his intelligence.
整个地球二号
All of Earth-2.
被消除了
Wiped out.
他甚至都不知道
And he doesn't even know it.
那不是你的错
But that wasn't your fault.
不是吗
Wasn't it?
当监视者把超能力还给我去面对危机时
When the Monitor gave me my powers back, for Crisis,
我记得我曾有多么强大
I remembered how powerful I used to be.
我控制不住的想到如果我没有停止做震波
I can't help thinking that if I hadn't stopped being Vibe,
也许我就能感应到第一道反物质波
maybe I could have sensed that first anti-matter wave.
也许我就能救下他
Maybe I could have saved them.
这就是为什么你对所有新的威胁
And that's why you've become so obsessed
这么执着的原因
with all the new threats.
你想要的保护每一个在始源地球活下来的人
You want to protect everyone who did survive on Earth Prime.
西斯科  你后悔
Cisco, do you regret
服用了超能力者解药吗
taking the meta-human cure?
不后悔
No.
你怀念做震波吗
Do you miss being Vibe?
凯特琳  这没那么简单
Caitlin, it's not that simple.
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道
You know...
我想你可能触及到了什么
I think you might be onto something over here.
对于所有新的威胁
With all these new threats,
我们现实所发生的改变
changes to our reality,
我们需要找个人把所有事情都整理好
we need someone whose job it is to compile all of them.
这个人要记得
Somebody who remembers the difference
改变前与改变后的不同
between the way it was and the way it is.
没错  不过...
Yeah, but...
你所说的事
what you're talking about,
是不可能在一天之内完成的
that can't just be done in a day.
更别提要是在
And it certainly can't be done
中城中间的某间屋子里了
in some room in the middle of Central City.
我知道
I know.
但我还是认为你是这项任务的不二之选
But I still think you're the man for the job.
再说了  也许离开中城一段时间
Besides, maybe some time away from Central City
能够让你想清楚  在这个后危机世界
will allow you to figure out who you want to be
你想成为一个什么样的人
in this post-Crisis world.
也许吧
Maybe.
本地新闻
麦克洛奇召开有关公民诉讼制度的新闻发布会
给你
Here you go.
谢了
Thanks.
那么  你想告诉我吗
So you gonna tell me?
你的想法
Your thinking.
报道这个新闻
Running this story.
我知道我要做什么  爸
I knew what I was doing, Dad.
真的吗  爱瑞丝  冰霜告诉我
Really, Iris? Frost told me.
你这是五级烧伤
You have fifth-degree burns.
我的鉴证人员在你的办公室检查了数个小时
My forensics guys have been in your office
但他们什么都没有找到
for hours, and they found nothing.
现场没有弹孔  也没有弹壳
There's no bullet holes, there's no casings.
如果那个杀手要是...
If that assassin would have...
在今天杀了你
murdered you today,
我都没有证据可以把她逮捕归案
I would have no evidence to bring her in.
黑洞袭击了我的办公室
Black Hole attacked my office.
爸  他们差点杀了我的朋友
Dad, they nearly killed my friends.
他们就在我的面前杀死了我的线人
They murdered my source right in front of me.
他会死是因为我要他开口
He's dead because I asked him to speak up.
为了不让他枉死  我要把这组织背后的
And I have to honor that by exposing each and every
每一个人都曝光出来
person behind this organization,
所以抱歉  爸  如果你想要我放弃
so I'm sorry, Dad, if you want me to give up--
-我...  -你知道我不会那么说的
- I- - You know I wouldn't say that.
但这个组织已经运行了多年
But this organization has been in operation for years,
它们的根基远比你们知道的要深厚  爱瑞丝
and their roots run deeper than you have dug, Iris.
你没法在短期内赢得这场战争
You can't win this war in a day.
听着  你和巴里告诉我危机即将来临的时候
Look, when you and Barry told me that Crisis was coming,
我就已经下定决心
I was determined to solve
要尽可能多地去破案  因为天晓得
as many cases as I could because God knows
我还有多少时日
how many days I have left
能够做出一些改变
to make a difference.
但随后危机到来了
But then Crisis came.
巴里幸存了下来
Barry survived.
所以现在每一天我都要提醒我自己
So now I have to remind myself every single day
我们不再生活在危机模式中了
that we don't live in Crisis mode anymore.
我们现在有时间了
We have time now.
那我该怎么做  爸
So what am I supposed to do, Dad?
我怎么才能打败这些人
How am I supposed to fight these people?
首先要做的事情就是
Well, first thing's first.
不能再鲁莽地冲到前线
Don't go charging to the front line
好像你一无所有似的
like you have nothing to lose.
现在  说回你的线人
Now--okay, your source.
你确定他没有告诉任何其他人黑洞的事吗
Are you sure he hasn't told anyone else about Black Hole?
没有
No, no.
事实上  某个人知道这件事
Actually, someone else did know.
麦克洛奇总裁将于今日新闻发布会上发言
地下七层
是我
我想你应该已经送到那个礼物篮了吧
无需多虑
我从未失手过两次
你想吃点什么吗
Can I get you something to eat?
不  我不饿  爸爸  谢谢
No, I'm good, Dad. Thanks.
那喝杯水吧
How about a glass of water?
好的
Yeah, ok.
好主意  谢谢
Sounds good, thanks.
中招了
Gotcha.
放下武器
Lower your weapon, now.
你被包围了  把枪放在地板上
We've got you surrounded. Put it on the floor.
我演爱瑞斯还不错吧
Pretty good Iris, huh?
太厉害了  宝贝
Uncanny, babe.
现在轮到真身上场了
Now it's up to the real one.
重大新闻  麦克洛奇CEO将举行媒体发布会
您好  卡弗先生
Mr. Carver, hello.
韦斯特-艾伦女士  真是意外
Ms. West-Allen, what a surprise.
我知道
I know.
我的死讯的报道被严重夸张了
Reports of my death were greatly exaggerated.
小心点  外面有一大群记者
Oh, careful, there's a scrum of reporters
就在走廊里十几米的地方
20 yards down the hall.
现在可不太合适
Might not be the most convenient time
打电话叫你的超能力杀手
to call up your meta-assassin.
没有证据就做出这样严重的指控可不太好
That's quite the allegation to make without any evidence.
我有证据
Oh, no, there's evidence.
你亲手交给我的
You gave it to me.
你的麦克洛奇门卡
Your McCulloch ID.
含有反射紫外辐射的芯片
It uses a microchip that reflects ultraviolet radiation.
你的前雇员想要告诉我
And as your former employee tried to tell me,
10级许可  研发部  基恩·霍斯克
你的公司的反射枪
it's the same microchip inside your company's reflector gun
以及黑洞的徽章里的芯片和它一样
and inside Black Hole's badges.
黑洞一直在使用你们公司的光学科技
Black Hole has been using your optics technology for years,
绑架埃斯佩兰萨·加西亚这样
all while abducting metas like Esperanza Garcia
以光为基础的超能力者
who have light-based powers,
这正好是你的专业领域
your area of expertise.
你把马尔科姆·尚博德安排进基恩·霍斯克的部门
You placed Malcolm Strombard in Gene Huskk's division
让他在步枪上市前
so that he could obtain the rifle
就能拿到它
before it went to market.
然后将这把步枪交给
and then place said rifle in the hands
唯一一个可以给它充能的人
of the one person who could power it:
纪美代·霍西  也是你的私人刺客
Kimiyo Hoshi, your personal assassin.
你并不是被黑洞抢劫了
You weren't robbed by Black Hole.
你就是黑洞
You are Black Hole,
而且你一直利用麦克洛奇的资源
and you've been using McCulloch's resources
资助在全球的各种阴谋  包括走私超能力者
to power a global conspiracy in meta-human trafficking,
贩卖武器  雇凶杀人
weapons sales, and murder-for-hire.
可否请您发表评论
Now would you care to comment?
可以
I would.
但我觉得你还没有了解来龙去脉
But I don't think you have the whole story yet,
因为如果了解了  你怎么会任由家人冒险
because if you did, why would you be here trying to scare me
自己跑到这里吓唬我
while your family risks their lives for you?
快放下武器
Weapon down, now!
你是对的
You're right.
我今晚确实阻止不了黑洞
I can't stop Black Hole tonight.
但我不能再让你伤害别人
But I can't let you hurt anyone else.
所以我设下了一个死亡开关
Which is why I've set up a dead man's switch.
如果我  我的雇员  我的线人
If I, my employees, any of my sources,
我爱的人死亡
my loved ones die?
我手中所有将你和黑洞联系起来的资料
All the information I have tying you to Black Hole
就会立刻被公开出来
will be immediately released.
加油
Come on.
有意思
下一枪得打头了
去你的
Screw you.
所以  让你的朋友住手
So tell your friend to stand down.
取消礼品篮
就这样  你就这么走了吗
That's it? You're just leaving?
我遵守命令
I follow orders.
-卡弗先生  -卡弗先生
- Mr. Carver. - Mr. Carver.
感谢大家来此参会
Hi, thank you all so much for coming. Here--
鉴于新近出现的消息
Given new information that has come to light,
我决定  麦克洛奇科技公司
I have decided that McCulloch Technologies
会取消
will be dropping its lawsuit
针对中城市民报的诉讼
against Central City Citizen Media.
有提问吗
Any questions?
谢谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
我要暂时离开一段时间
I'm going away for a bit.
我的震波力量可能是没有了
I might not have my Vibe powers anymore,
但至少我还能做些
but at least I can still do
传统的体力型工作
some good, old-fashioned foot work,
所以我会去寻找
so I'm gonna go suss out
我们这个勇敢新世界所可能面临的
whatever brave new threats we might have
勇敢新威胁
to our brave new world.
我在想  这期间呢
And I was thinking, in the meantime,
也许你可以看着尖端科研实验室
maybe you could hold down the fort here at S.T.A.R. Labs.
等等  你...  你这有摄像头吧
Oh, wait, you-- you got cameras here?
这里没有摄像头
There's no cameras.
这是...  这是捉弄人的玩意吧
This is-- this is some kind of trick.
-对吧  -不是
- Right? - No.
不是捉弄人的
It's not a trick.
更像是橄榄枝
It's more of an olive branch.
很抱歉我说了那些话
I'm sorry I said those things.
危机中所发生的事
I should have held myself accountable
应该由我来承担责任
for what happened in Crisis,
而我却把火撒在你身上
but instead I chose to take it out on you.
算了  那么...
Anyway, so...
要上路了
Hitting the road?
我不在的时候  纳什·威尔斯
So while I'm gone, do your best
尽量别把什么东西搞坏  好吗
not to break anything, will you, Nashville?
你不在的时候把东西都搞坏  明白了
Break everything while you're gone, got it.
我说的话你真的是
It's like you're literally not listening
-完全没有听啊  -你说什么
- to what I'm saying. - What's that?
纳什
Nash?
但愿你能得偿所愿
I hope you find what you're looking for.
狄格尔在的炼狱怎么样
How was Lian Yu with Dig?
我以为奥利弗把面具留下来  是...
I thought Oliver left the mask as...
提醒我们要继续战斗的
a reminder to keep fighting.
但我们经历了这么多凶险
But with all the danger we've been through,
我想我有点
I guess I kind of
忘了最初给他做这个的原因了
forgot why I made it for him in the first place.
是为了让奥利弗永远记着
It was so Oliver would always remember
去保护他所爱的人们
to protect the people he loved.
所以他把它留给了我
That's why he left it to me.
他想让我接受我自己的忠告
He wanted me to take my own advice.
自从我们知道你会在危机中死掉以后
I've been in overdrive ever since
我就一直处在高速运转的状态
we learned that you were gonna die in Crisis.
过去的一个月  我把每一天都过的
I've spent the last month trying to live every day
像是我的最后一天那样  拼命地...
like it was my last, hell-bent on...
尽可能去珍惜我以为是我们俩在一起的
Trying to make the most of the limited time
最后的时光
I thought we had left together,
但危机结束了
but Crisis is over now,
而你没有死
and you didn't die.
我觉得我是  我忘了要...
And I think I just-- I forgot to--
慢下来
To slow down.
你是不是也想
So are you also thinking
今晚我们也许可以慢慢来
that tonight maybe we just take it easy?
英雄所见略同
Great minds.
是佳人所见略同
Beautiful minds.
闪电侠
天啊
Oh, my God.
镜子
Mirror.
伊娃
Eva.
伊娃·麦克洛奇创造性的反射型芯片技术打破了预期
麦克洛奇技术公司创始人和首席执行官
伊娃·麦克洛奇失踪
10级权限
研发
外出追查一个线索
非常急迫
爱你
你在蓄谋什么  伊娃·麦克洛奇
What were you up to, Eva McCulloch?